雷霆壮志
欢迎莅临参观  地通拿500大赛
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Daytona 500,
超级碗机车大赛
the Super Bowl of motor racing events.
两届冠军
Walking onto the grid is the two-time
班洛甸正步向起点
Daytona 500 and defending champion Rowdy Burns.
他的劲敌是宾夕凡尼亚州车手  宾雅度
And perennial contender from Reading, Pennsylvania, Aldo Bennedetti.
各位选手，请开动引擎
Gentlemen, start your engines.
四十三号是帕列察…
Big turn back for number 43, Richard Petty.
帕列察遇上意外
Petty spins to the inside of the track.
转向赛道内侧
A tough break for Richard Petty.
帕列察中途退出大赛
Richard Petty is out of the Daytona 500.
著名领队霍哈利
Speaking of people who are out of the race,
没参加这届赛事
perhaps it's time to remember the legendary crew chief, Harry Hogge,
他的爱将白毕地在去年比赛…
whose great driver, Buddy Bretherton, died here last year in a fiery crash,
连人带车冲向墙边，车毁人亡
hitting the wall at over 195 miles an hour.
哈利，你在这里享受人生
So you're enjoying the good life, Harry?
对啊
Yeah.
我不讨厌施肥
I never minded spreading a little fertilizer around now and then.
有些工作比施肥更讨厌
There's worse things.
这部机车怎样？ 不错
- How's the truck running? - Runs good.
帮我装嵌一部车
I want you to build me a car.
添  汽车商人
Now, Tim, everybody knows some downtown car dealer
花不起钱派队参赛
can't afford a race team.
没有车手会跟你签约
No driver worth a damn is gonna sign with you.
如果车撞毁了  你没钱装嵌新车
'Cause they wreck one car, you can't afford to build them another
车手就要退出赛事
and they're out of the deal, you know.
没有车手
And no car's gonna win without a driver.
又怎能胜出
Not even mine.
你装嵌赛车，我会找车手
If you built the car, I'd get a damn driver.
赛季开始了  还会有什么车手？
What kind of driver are you going to find after the season's started?
剩下来的都是车场败将
Some old boy who's washed up and wasn't worth a shit to begin with.
你可以训练他
You can work with him.
训练车手就和装嵌赛车一样
You can build a driver like you build a car, Harry.
添，看看那头猎狗
Tim, take a look at that hound.
那是最出色的猎狗
That's the best coon dog I've ever seen or heard about.
我可从没有训练它  我找到车手了
- And I didn't teach him a damn thing. - Well, I got somebody.
谁？ 你去看看他
- Who? - Take a look at him.
若是好手早已经冒出头来
Anybody I gotta take a look at, ain't somebody.
那就看看这无名之辈吧
Then take a look at nobody.
我已经放弃赛车了，你知道的
Look, Tim, I gave up racing. You gotta know that. All right?
你没有放弃赛车
You didn't give up racing, Harry.
你不想他们调查白毕地的死因
You quit to avoid an investigation into Buddy's crash at Daytona.
我没有逃避调查
Hey, I didn't avoid any goddamn investigation.
我跟赛车会谈过
Anyway, I talked to NASCAR
如果你复出  他们不会调查旧事
and if you come back in there won't be any investigation.
你怎样说服他们？
How the hell did you sell them on that deal?
我是一流的推销员
I'm a hell of a salesman.
那才是真正的赛车手
Now, that's a racecar driver.
你的车手什么时候来？
When's your driver due?
哈利说你的选手  在印第安纳比赛
Harry tells me your guy runs those Indy type deals.
他参加短程赛
Yeah. Sprints, mainly.
赢了很多奖项
Two World of Outlaw championships, three all-star wins,
曾经连赢七次大赛  现在是赛车会会员
seven straight feature wins and he's been driving ASA.
嘿！
Hey.
做了不少统计
Got yourself a real statistician there.
他懂得发掘车手？
Does he know anything about drivers?
等着看好了
We'll see.
你那车手来自什么地方？
Harry, where'd you say your driver's from?
鹰石镇
Eagle Rock.
接近威斯波尔市？
It's up around Wilkesboro, isn't it?
不，接近格伦代尔市，加州
No. Glendale, California.
他是北方佬？
He's a Yankee?
加州人不算是北方佬
Not exactly. If you're from California, you're not a Yankee.
他们不伦不类
You're not really anything.
说得对
You said it.
避震器很好
The shocks are right, we're dialed in, buddy.
不必改动
Don't change a thing.
终于不再耕田
Hey, you ain't buried in horse manure after all.
你气色不错  你状态很好
- Looking pretty good. - You're the one who's looking good.
我花了不少工夫
It hadn't been easy, Harry, I'll guaran-damn-tee you,
现在它是最棒的
but this bitch is ready to run.
洛甸， 谢谢你
I can't tell you how much we all appreciate
借出这部车
you letting us use the car, Rowdy.
我跟你说过的
I told you about this, Rowdy.
哈利的新手
Harry's got some new driver
要借用它跑两个圈
and he needs a car just to turn a couple of laps.
霍哈利亲自请我们帮忙
I told you it was Harry Hogge who'd asked us personally, as a favor.
这新手是谁？
Who is this driver?
添说你一直参加短程赛
Tim tells me you've been running open-wheels.
对
That's right.
现在想参加长程比赛
And now you just want to up and drive NASCAR?
对
That's right.
你对这些比赛有什么认识？
What do you know about stock car racing?
我在电视上看过
Well, I've watched it on television, of course.
在电视上看过？
You've seen it on television?
体育台报导详尽
ESPN, the coverage is excellent.
我获益良多
You'd be surprised at how much you can pick up.
我相信你
I'm sure I would.
你还是别开这部车
Look, this may not be the best time for you to run this car.
有什么问题？
Was there some problem?
没有
No, sir. You all go right ahead.
开车吧，如果你弄坏我的车
But you bend this bitch the least little bit,
我会阉了你
I'm gonna tear your balls off.
请你替我… 拿着它
Okay. Would you mind very much holding on to this?
你听见了？
Didn't he hear what that man said?
慢着，我们要谈谈
Hold on a minute. Don't you think we ought to talk?
你想教我开车？好
What? About how I'm gonna run? Sure.
你竟然会活到今天
About how you've managed to live as long as you have.
你不能开这部车
Look, I ain't gonna let you race this car.
你怎么了？ 他改变主意
- What's going on? - He's had second thoughts.
-你答应我来看他  -已经看了
- You said you'd look at him. - I've looked at him.
我花了二千五百元租跑道
I paid $2,500 to use this track today, Harry.
他想找名牌赞助商、名牌车手
Forget it. He needs a brand name like Exxon or Richard Petty.
谁是好车手我看得出来
Well, I know a damn race driver when I see one.
怎么了？就此告吹？
What's going on, Harry? Is this happening or what?
请帮帮忙
Do us all a favor, Harry.
让我开车，我不会令你失望
Let me drive. I won't make a fool out of you.
隧道弯很危险
That tunnel turn's real tricky.
无论冷或暖，那里滑得要命
Now, whether it's hot or cold, it gets as slick as a butt.
稍一不慎
Then you'll slip and slide
就会撞向墙边
and slam yourself into the wall before you know it.
你要慢慢来
So just take it easy.
我要踩尽油门  不要
- I'm dropping the hammer. - No, you're not.
比洛甸还要快
It's under Rowdy's time.
还可以更快
Well, it might have been better if he cracked up the car.
很快  是吗？
- That was fast. - Yeah?
三十一秒
Thirty-one flat.
足以在上次赛事取胜
That's good enough to take the pole in the last race here.
真是难以置信
Hell, I thought this was gonna be a joke.
你从来没开过这类车？ 我开过短程车
- You never drove a stock car before? - No, sprints mainly.
你叫什么名字？ 白贝克，你呢？
- What's your name? - Buck Bretherton. What's yours?
我叫狄高，幸会
Cole Trickle. It's damn nice to meet you, Buck.
幸会，狄高
Damn nice to meet you, too, Cole.
你很幸运，拐隧道弯的时候
You were one lucky son of a bitch in that tunnel turn.
只差一点就会失控出事
That car was way out of shape.
靠运气？我可以再来一次
Well, if you think it was luck, let's do it again.
跑得很好  谢谢
- You run good. - Thank you.
比赛时你能否从车群中冲出来
Now, go get your own car and we'll see how you do in a crowd.
怎么不继续参加短程赛？
So, how come you don't stick to open wheels?
我被取消资格
I lost my ride.
赢了那么多赛事  你被解雇？
After two championships and seven straight wins, you were fired?
我被取消资格
I lost my ride.
难道我不能退出？
Doesn't matter. I'd have quit regardless.
为什么？ -继续下去也没意思
- Why's that? - I wasn't going anywhere.
-你想做什么？ 参加印第安纳赛事
- Where do you want to go? - Indianapolis.
但我没有好车
But you can't win in Indy without a great car.
不能参赛
And my name's not Andretti or Unser.
所有参赛的车都是一样
On the other hand, stock cars are stock cars. Pretty much the same.
它们才不一样
Hey, there's nothing stock about a stock car.
我无意冒犯你
Look, I'm not trying to insult you.
参赛跑车都是性能均等的
All I'm saying is, stock cars are built to run equal.
对吗？-规则上说
- Isn't that right? - So the rule books say.
所以我不必担心因为车的性能而败
So I don't have to worry about getting beat by another car.
只担心
In other words, all you have to worry about
被技术更好的车手打败
- is getting beat by other drivers. - Yeah.
你为我嵌车  我会成为地通拿冠军
You build me a car, and I'll win Daytona next year.
我把引擎安装得更贴近地面
I'm gonna give you an engine low to the ground.
把油盘加大，减低风阻
Extra-big oil pan that'll cut the wind from underneath you.
你会增强三、四十匹马力
That'll give you 30 to 40 more horsepower.
我会增加你的汽油储存量
I'm gonna give you a fuel line that'll hold an extra gallon of gas.
我会把你雕琢成子弹一样
I'm gonna shave half an inch off you and shape you like a bullet.
我们为你加油、喷漆  量度重量
And when we get you primed, painted and weighed,
然后你可以登上跑道，听到吗
you're going to be ready to go out on that racetrack. You hear me?
你将会十全十美
You're gonna be perfect.
(狄高)
(亚里桑那州，凤凰城)
我要好好教训这新手
Okay. I'm going to pull this rookie's chain.
你左摇右摆
Cole, you're wandering all over the track.
那杂种向我撞过来
Yeah. Well, that son of a bitch just slammed into me.
他没有撞你，也没有推你
No, he didn't slam into you, he didn't bump you, he didn't nudge you.
这叫做磨擦，磨擦乃兵家常事
He rubbed you, and rubbing, son, is racing.
沙板报销了
There goes the fender.
前沙板也报销了
There goes the quarter panel.
准备
All right. Get back!
好了，既然现在不准爬头
All right, while we're still under a caution,
你去撞领航车吧
I want you to go back out on that track and hit the pace car.
撞领航车？ 撞领航车
- Hit the pace car? - Hit the pace car!
为什么？
What for?
你什么车都撞过了
Because you hit every other goddamn thing out there.
只欠领航车  走吧…
I want you to be perfect. Now, go on. Go! Go! Go!
(田纳西州，布里斯托)
你得返回中线  混账
You're going too high. Stay in the group.
看看这里  至少不用修理这一边
How about that? This side we don't have to fix.
我不想宠坏你
I don't want you spoiled, Buck.
(特拉华州，多佛尔)
将会损伤惨重
This is gonna hurt.
跑开…
Move! Move! Move!
看到那家伙吗？
Did you see that guy?
(北卡罗来纳州，洛京咸)
我要回站
I've got to pit.
不行，我们很忙
I don't think so. We're busy now.
什么？ 我们在吃雪糕
- You're what? - We're eating ice cream.
吃雪糕？
Ice cream?
你可以来拿甜筒
Now, you're welcome to come on and get one,
但大会可能会
but I don't believe NASCAR
反对你吃雪糕
would think much of you trying to eat an ice cream cone out there.
只是开车你已经应付不来
You have enough trouble riding around the track as it is.
放松些
Take it easy.
高，别这样
Come on now, Cole!
高
Cole! Cole!
周日的赛事我们一塌糊涂
We messed up big-time on Sunday.
当时有赞助商在看台
I had sponsors in the stands
我跟他们握手
and I'm hugging and holding hands
我讨好他们  我希望你们有所表现
and kissing them in the air and praying for a good showing.
结果怎样？
And what do we do?
你们闹得天翻地覆
We end up looking like a monkey fucking a football out there.
请你们出去
Everybody out, please.
你们两个留下来
Except you two.
我有一个问题
I've got a question.
要做什么才可以胜出？
What is the one thing you absolutely need to do to win a race?
-很简单  -住口
- It's pretty damn obvious... - You keep quiet!
你要完成赛事
You need to finish the race.
添，我知道哈利是老行尊
Tim, I realize Harry's been around a long time.
我不是批评他落后
I'm not saying that his ways are antiquated
但他的引擎
but it'd help to have a car that handled properly
常常烧坏
and didn't blow engines.
他不停加快转速
Well, if he wouldn't get excited and over rev the son of a bitch,
引擎才会烧坏
the engine wouldn't blow.
高，转波的时候…
Now, Cole, when you shift the gear,
指针跳向红色地带
and that little needle on the tach goes into the red
指着九千转  那是凶兆
and reads 9,000 rpm, that's bad.
爆胎也是我的错
It's also my fault if the tires blow, if you ask this old fart.
当然是你的错
Well, hell yes, it's your fault.
其余四十位选手
There's 40 other vultures out there
都没有爆胎
who managed to finish the race on their tires.
你见过华丹卢爆胎吗？
You see Darrell Waltrip using up his tires?
赛车难不倒我
There's nothing I can't do with a racecar.
我可没办法
Well, that's the difference between you and me.
修好你的车  这很明显
- There's only so much I can do! - That's obvious.
哈利，他不需要明白你的工作
Harry, he doesn't need to appreciate your job to do his.
不了解赛车的性能
Well, he sure as hell does. How can he expect to race
他怎可以上场比赛？
if he don't know what a racecar can and can't do?
你想怎样？
What is this shit, huh?
我留在修理站，你去赛车？
You want me to work the pit and you drive?
好吧
Fine. We'll try that.
这杂种真是不可理喻
I can't talk to this son of a bitch.
这杂种不可理喻，我不能…
I can't talk to that son of a bitch. I really can't. I can't...
他可以出赛吗？
- You think he can drive? - He can drive.
当然可以，他把车胎、引擎
He can drive beyond the limits of the tires,
整架跑车都消耗尽
the engine, the car, anything else.
如果他肯听从我  我们就不会输
If the son of a bitch listened to me, we wouldn't hardly ever lose a race.
如果以后两场赛事  还找不到赞助商
If we don't get us a sponsor in the next couple of races,
我死定了
my ass is fried.
我会输掉所有生意
I'm liable to be out of the car business altogether.
哈利，你是有实力的  你也知道你有实力
And, Harry, I know you're great. You know you're great.
但车手不信任你
But if the guy in the car doesn't trust you,
我们无法取胜
we're never going to win a damn race.
哈利
Hey, Harry.
我们得谈谈，好吗？
We've gotta talk, all right?
好，说吧
All right, Harry. Talk.
在赛车时…
No. On the radio during the race.
如果想节节领先
Now, you wanna run right on the ragged edge all the damn time,
你要把跑车的状态说出来
you've got to tell us what's going on with the car.
你想改变我的驾驶方法
Or you just want to change the way I drive it.
可能吧
Maybe.
你应该改装跑车来迁就我
Well, maybe you can set up the car so I don't have to change.
好
I'd be happy to.
告诉我怎么改  你想知道什么？
- You just tell me how. - What do you want to know?
你才是司机
Well, hell, Cole, you are the driver.
你知道跑车的缺点
You think she's running loose or tight? Tell us.
我们调整它
We give a turn here, take some wedge out there,
去除旧患，这样就可以胜出
we'll win some races. That's all there is to it.
我办不到  为什么？
- I can't do that. - Why the hell not?
因为我听不懂你的话
Because I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
什么意思？
How do you mean that?
我不了解汽车，明白吗
Because I don't know much about cars, okay?
所有车手
Well, hey, Cole, that don't make you
都跟你一样
a damn bit different from any driver I ever met.
我是真的不了解汽车
No, I mean, I really don't know.
你说调整什么零件
I don't know what you just said about a turn here and a wedge there.
我一窍不通  完全不懂
- I don't know. I don't know. - How can that be?
有什么不同吗？
What's the difference?
他们叫我赛车，因为我会飚车
They told me to get in a car and drive. And I could drive.
我也想帮你，但无能为力
The point is, I'd like to help out but I can't.
我没知识，什么也说不出来
I'm an idiot. I don't have the vocabulary.
-这样…  -怎样？
- Well... - Well?
我们得想个办法，对不对？
We're just gonna have to figure one out, aren't we?
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
好吧
All right?
它怎样？
How does she feel?
屁股摆来摆去
Her ass is all over the place.
车尾摇摆不定，车速太快
Well, the rear end's loose. Car's fast.
你开得太快，快要失控
"Loose" is fast, and "on the edge," you're out of control.
还有一件事
Now, Cole, there is something else.
轮胎是取胜的关键
Tires is what wins a race.
你说什么？
Yeah. What the hell are you talking about?
如果车胎过热
If we can't figure you a way to run so you don't melt the damn tires,
便跑不完全程
we can't finish a race.
你想怎样？
So, what do you want?
用你的方法
I'll tell you what,
跑五十圈  然后用我的方法跑五十圈
you run 50 laps any way you like, then 50 laps like I want you to.
诚实地比试一下，我会打败你
Give me an honest run. If you do, I'm gonna beat you.
现在用我的方法跑五十圈
All right. Now we're going to do it 50 laps my way, all right?
你在印第安纳作赛的时候
Now, when you were racing Indy cars out west,
轮胎宽一倍，车身轻一倍
the tires were twice as wide and the car weighed half as much.
现在车身重一倍，轮胎窄一倍
Now your car weighs twice as much and the tires are half as wide
你令车胎过度受热
and you're burning them up, all right.
它们会溶化
Now, if you do... When you burn them up, they melt,
变得滑溜
when they melt, they get greasy and you slip and slide.
你会滑胎失控  明白了？
And you're out of control. All right?
去吧  好了
Let's go!
他的方法  我的方法
His way, my way.
我的方法快了六秒
I was six seconds faster.
去公路餐厅请我吃午餐吧
You can buy me some lunch at the highway joint, Tim.
(南卡罗来纳州，达令顿)
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我们要谋求对策
We're trying to figure out what to do.
什么事？ 什么事？我们有麻烦了
- About what? - About what? We're in trouble.
洛甸的圈速是30.25秒
Rowdy took the pole in 30.25.
我们是31.10秒  慢了差不多一秒
We run 31.10. We're almost a second off the pace.
要想办法令它跑得更快
We're looking for some speed out of this.
这跑车已经十全十美
The car's perfect, Harry.
本季首个赛事
It's the first race of the season here
在达令顿赛道举行
at the legendary Darlington International Speedway.
最危险的地方是四号弯角
And the most treacherous turn is number four.
圈速落后了零点一秒
30:90. Leader's 30:80.
你排第十二位  -还有三十圈
You're running 12th. Thirty laps to go.
-谢谢
Thanks, Harry.
轮胎会过热，你要慢下来
You're gonna burn the damn tires, Cole. So take it easy.
我没有加速，是其他人慢了
Harry, I'm not going faster. Everybody else is going slower.
他说得对，我们测了圈速
He's right, Harry. I checked his lap times.
是其他人的圈速减慢了
We just haven't fallen off as much as everybody else.
对，你做得很好
That's right. You're doing good, Cole. You're doing real good.
你排第五位
You're running fifth
圈速比第一位快半秒
and you're gaining half a second a lap on the leader.
还要跑十五圈
Fifteen to go.
不要在四号弯角抢外线
Don't pass on the outside of turn four.
对了，走内线  还有十圈
That's right. Stay to the inside, Cole. Ten laps to go.
狄高升至第二位
And Trickle has moved into the number two spot,
紧随班洛甸
right behind Rowdy Burns.
-我追着第一位  -还有五圈
- I'm right behind the leader. - Five laps to go.
记得我吗？
Remember me?
你做什么？
What in the hell's going on?
轻轻磨擦对手  磨擦乃兵家常事
Just a little rubbing, Harry. Rubbing's racing.
我要和这新丁作个了断
I'm going to take this rookie once and for all.
好了，够了
All right, God damn it. That's enough!
别惹洛甸
You can't play with Rowdy like this.
他不会放过你
He's gonna give you a real ass ripping.
别紧张
Just relax, Harry.
两雄相遇，最后洛甸被撵走
Somebody's got to give. And it's Rowdy Burns who's out!
他竟然卷土重来
No! An incredible recovery by Rowdy.
继续比赛
He retains his position on the lead lap.
现在由狄高领先
And we have a new leader.
他开着46号雪佛莱
Cole Trickle in the number 46 City Chevrolet Car.
车手暂时不准爬头，剩下三圈
We're under caution with three laps to go.
暂时不准爬头，回修理站  为什么？我快要冲线了
- Caution's out. Come on in. - What for? It's almost over.
你跑了六十八圈  总要回修理站
You've been on the green for 68 laps. Everybody's got to pit, Cole.
快点…
Go, go! Go, go!
气枪坏了，拿枪来
The air gun's jammed, give me another one.
给我拿气枪
- Give me a gun. Give me a gun. - It's jammed.
快点
Come on, switch it, guys.
快点  换胎吧
Let's go!
混账，快点… 装上去吧
Damn it! Go! Go! Go! Go. Get them on quick!
该死，狗娘养的
God damn it! Son of a bitch!
-高…  -狗娘养的
Now, Cole...
-狗娘养的  -我们听到你说话
- Son of a bitch! - Cole, we're on the air, all right?
本来跑第一位
I come into the pit, I'm in first place.
现在变第三位，只剩下两圈
I go out, I'm in third with two laps to go.
先冷静下来
All right. First of all, don't get excited, all right.
第三位是好位置
You're in third place. That's a pretty respectable position.
你要这样做…
Now, what you do is this.
他们在四号弯角减速
When they slow down into turn four,
你加速
you just keep your foot on the gas
在外线爬头
and drive right by them on the outside.
你说没有人会在四号弯抢外线
Harry, you told me, nobody goes to the outside on turn four.
我改变口风
Well, now I'm telling you different.
走外线吧，你不会失控
If you go to the outside, you can hold it.
他会撞向墙边
He's going to end up in the wall.
领航车快要离开
All right. Cole, the pace car is about ready to duck on off.
我们没时间考虑
We don't have a whole lot of time to talk about this.
为什么不会失控
Well, tell me how.
我们为你换了特制轮胎
It's 'cause we've got a real good set of match tires on.
什么？
- What? - What?
这些轮胎完美匹配
Those tires are matched perfect and staggered special.
你会害死他
You're gonna get him killed.
领航车快要离开
Pace car's about ready to duck on off.
跑外线吧，不会出轨的
If you go to the outside, you can hold it.
好吧，你比我更了解这部车
All right, Harry. When it comes to the car I'll take your word.
白旗出来了，这是最后一圈
The white flag is out. One lap to go.
我看那小子不敢抢外线爬头
The boy don't have the balls to pass me on the outside.
他们直闯四号弯角
And they're heading into treacherous turn four.
好
Yes!
狄高首次胜出
And Cole Trickle wins his first ever NASCAR victory.
班洛甸得第二名
Second place goes to Rowdy Burns.
狄高
Cole Trickle...
你知道
Cole, did you have any idea
自己能够
you could run the car wide open into that last turn
在急弯爬头？
and make it stick like that?
我信心十足
- I knew it all along. - How's that?
嗯，在最后一站，当我进来时，哈里倒换上了特殊轮胎
Well, in our last stop, when I came in, Harry put on special tires.
特制轮胎？它们有什么特点？
Special tires? Harry Hogge, what's special about them?
没什么特别…
Well, nothing in particular.
霍哈利要向车手好好解释
Looks like Harry Hogge has a little explaining to do.
但你说…
You told me...
我说谎
I lied. I had to tell you something to calm you down.
这样你才会冷静下来
You were acting like such a candy-ass.
气枪故障，你气急败坏  没法子专心比赛
After the air gun stuck, I figured you'd never get back on the racetrack.
你这狗娘养的
You son of a bitch!
试戴这顶帽子  我们找到赞助商了
Try this on for size. We've got ourselves a sponsor.
答应我一件事
Promise me one thing, boys,
无论怎样，定要赢地通拿大赛
whatever else we do from here, we win Daytona.
-好  -一言为定  一言为定
That's a promise. That's a promise.
出售毫无价值的矿场股票
Selling thousands of dollars worth of useless mining stock
简直是挂羊头卖狗肉
and they call that a dog and pony show.
你觉得可笑  一旦发生在你身上  你就笑不出来
It may be funny, but it's not that funny when it happens to you, son.
的确发生在我身上
It happened to me.
你买了矿场股票？
What? You bought worthless mining stock?
我被取消赛车资格
I told you I lost my ride.
因为
That's how I lost it.
车队的老板是老千
Team owner was a conman. Junk bonds, worthless companies.
他出售偷回来的游艇
But mainly he sold stolen yachts.
我赢了赛事  他利用我的名气促销
When I won enough races, he even used my name to promote the sales.
结果他坐牢，我不能赛车
He went to jail and I lost my ride.
真是羞耻
It was pretty humiliating, actually.
你被卑鄙小人陷害
Hell, Cole, there's no need to be embarrassed
不必觉得羞耻
by some lowlife, piece of trash who put you in that kind of position.
那要看情形
- Well, Harry, that depends. - On what?
你是否和那个卑鄙小人有亲戚关系，一个垃圾人
On whether or not you're related to that lowlife, piece of trash.
他是我父亲
He was my father.
自从那次之后
I've never really stuck with anything since.
他们不相信我，我也不信他们
They don't trust me, I don't trust them.
这个你最清楚
You know how that goes.
举例说
Like for instance,
你今天对我说谎
you lied to me today.
没有撞车送命是我好运
It was dumb luck I didn't end up crashed or dead.
我应该揍你一顿  是吗？ 来吧
- I ought to punch you out. - Yeah? Give it a try.
不
No.
跟六十岁老翁打架？
Don't wanna get my ass kicked by a 60-year-old man.
五十九岁
Fifty-nine.
哈利，教训他  高，加油
- Whoop his ass, Harry. - Come on, Cole.
他占了上风
Oh, God. Come on.
车手不应该抢外线爬头
Drivers just don't go to the outside like that, Cole.
但我知道你应付得来  我知道的
But I knew you could do it. I knew it.
我对你有信心
I believed it in my heart.
桃还是樱桃？ 樱桃
- Peach or cherry? - Cherry.
你是独一无二的
I'm taking a leak.
有深谋远虑的车手
There you see now, there's calculating drivers,
也有英勇无畏的车手
and then there's kamikaze drivers.
高就像我父亲，勇者无惧
And our Cole here's a kamikaze, like my pappy was.
谁是你父亲？ 白毕地
- And who's that? - Buddy Bretherton.
白毕地是你父亲？ 是
Buddy Bretherton was your dad?
他在地通拿大赛去世  是去年的事
- He died at Daytona, didn't he? - Last year.
是什么原因？ 撞向墙边
- How did it happen? Mind my asking? - He hit the wall.
哪个弯口？
Which turn?
可能在撞墙前去世
He was probably dead before he hit it.
法医官说他心脏病发
The coroner's report showed massive heart attack.
我们被截停了
I believe we've been pulled over.
所有人下车面壁站好
All right. Everybody out and up against the wall here.
你们被捕了
You're under arrest.
立刻下车
Let's go. Move it.
什么事？ 你拿着的东西
- What the hell for? - It's right there in your hand.
非法运酒越过州界
Transportation of illegal alcohol across state lines
作贩卖用途
for the purpose of distribution.
你误会了，长官
Well, I don't know what this looks like to you, Officer,
我们没卖酒，我们不过在喝酒
but this is not distribution. This is consumption.
那仍然是犯法
Well, that don't exactly make it legal.
你应该清楚
You know what...
转身站好
Now up against the wall.
什么事？ 面壁站好
- What... What is this? - Up against the wall!
长官
Officer?
找到一些东西
Well, looks like we've found something.
-什么？ -他藏着武器
- What's that? - A concealed weapon.
在哪里？ 这里
- Where? - Right here.
余下来的问题是…
Now, the only question is,
他会否动用武器？ 好…
will he actually use it?
不要生气
Please don't be mad.
他们说你可能喜欢我
Harry and the boys just thought you might like me.
这里是佛罗里达州地通拿
Here we are for summer speed weeks in Daytona Beach, Florida.
今天举行
It's the Firecracker 400.
新晋车手狄高备受瞩目
And the favorite here today is newcomer Cole Trickle
驾驶46号雪佛莱
in the number 46 Superflo Chevrolet.
赛车史上最厉害的年轻车手
He's the hottest young rookie in NASCAR history
六场比赛胜出五场，史无前例
and has won an unprecedented five out of his last six races.
别对着洛甸的倒后镜扮鬼脸
Stop playing peek-a-boo in Rowdy's rearview mirror.
不要再这么幼稚
I thought you boys would've had enough of that by now.
我没有看他的倒后镜
I'm not doing anything like that, Harry.
你做什么？
Well, then what are you doing?
他冲过来  撞松了自己的灭音器
He rubbed me the wrong way and loosened his bumper!
我帮他脱下整个灭音器
I'm just gonna have to come all the way out.
他的泵把
Try that and his rear bumper's liable to go through the radiator
会撞坏你的水箱
and take you out of the whole damn race.
泵把松脱就要退出比赛
That bumper gets any looser, Rowdy, they're gonna black-flag you.
让他走吧
Let him go by.
他挥手让我爬头，我走外线
He's waving me by, I'm gonna take him on the high side.
你担心什么？
What are you so worried about, Harry?
你令我吓一跳，做得好
Well, you surely got my attention. Great driving, great recovery, Cole.
狄高紧随51号的班洛甸
Cole Trickle now right behind the number 51 car of Burns,
再次展开龙争虎斗
and they go at it again.
四号弯角撞车
There's a crash coming out of turn four, Cole.
我看到了
I see it!
-你听到吗？ -我看不见
Can you hear me?
请摇动手指
- I can't see anything. - Wiggle your fingers for me.
和脚趾
Wiggle your toes.
我什么也看不见
I can't see anything.
我没事
I'm all right. Take this off.
他怎么了？
Hey, what do we got?
接上监察器
Hook up the other monitor.
我不是电池，不用充电
I'm not a car battery. I don't need recharging.
放松，这是正常程序
Relax, it's just standard procedure.
去你的  你说什么？
- Hey, you go screw yourself, okay? - What was that, Mr. Burns?
我不是说你
- I wouldn't tell you to do that, Doc. - We'll see.
发生什么事？
- What's going on? - Keep your head down.
你在医院
- Relax. - You're in a hospital.
我盲了
I can't see.
发生什么事？
God, tell me what's going on! I'm blind, God damn it!
你叫什么名字？ -什么？
- What's your name? - What...
-你叫什么名字？ 狄高
- What's your name? - Cole. Cole.
高，请不要动
Cole, would you help us out and lie still, please?
-送他到扫瞄房  -是
- C-spine and CAT scan, right away. - Yes, Doctor.
可否摇动你的手指？
Can you move your fingers for me?
他脑部受了震荡
Just tell him he's had a concussion.
有瘀伤和肿胀
His brain is bruised, and like any bruise, it's gonna swell.
所以他的视力受了影响
Now that swelling is almost certainly what's affecting his vision.
你的脑部受到震荡
You have a concussion and your brain is bruised
有瘀伤和肿胀  所以你的视力受影响
and it's going to swell. It's certainly gonna affect your vision.
我会恢复视力吗？
You mean this will go away?
告诉他我们会继续检查
Tell him we're gonna run some tests to confirm everything.
他的头盔有没有爆裂？
What did his helmet look like and was it cracked?
没有
No.
有没有划痕？ 你是脑科医生？
- Was it scratched? - Are you a brain doctor?
头盔前面还是后面有划痕？
Was the helmet scratched at the front or the back?
我相信前后都有
I believe it was scratched in the back and the front.
你是脑科医生？
Are you a brain doctor?
请跟我说话
Could someone talk to me?
赛车时有人用无线电跟我说话
When I'm driving, I got a guy on the radio who talks to me.
我看不见他
I can't see him.
但他会跟我说话
But he talks to me.
别担心，我们会照顾他
Don't worry, we're going to take care of him.
哈利
Harry.
你没事吧  没事，为什么？
- Are you okay, Harry? - Yeah. Why?
你看来弯弯曲曲的
You look all bent out of shape.
是我的眼睛有问题吧
Hell, it's probably just my eyes.
是我变形了，我整晚留在这里
No, it's me, I've been here all night.
他们给我吃什么药
Jesus. What are they giving me here?
哈利，发生什么事？
Harry, what happened?
在跑道上打转的时候…
Rowdy was spinning across the track.
我应该往前直冲
The rule is you go straight for them.
我没有放慢速度
So I never took my foot off the gas.
前面那部车早应该离开了  但它还在那里
He should have been gone by the time I got there, man, but he wasn't.
另一部车撞你  然后撞向班洛甸
I think another car hit you and knocked you into Rowdy.
那部车突然冒出来
- He came out of nowhere. - Yeah.
这是很罕有的意外
It's one of those things that never happens.
别想它了
I wouldn't even think about it, you know.
我去找医生来  我觉得很好  好
- I'll get the doctor. - I feel great.
高
Cole.
见到你真好，高
Damn nice to see you, Cole.
你好吗？
How you doing, buddy?
见到你真好，贝克
It's damn nice to see you, Buck.
你觉得怎样？
How you doing?
高，你见过廖医生了
Cole, you've met Dr. Lewicki.
她是你的医生，廖医生
That's your doctor, Dr. Lewicki.
当时他看不见我
I don't think he's actually seen me before.
哈利，你又来了
Sure, Harry.
-不  -廖医生
- No... - Dr. Lewicki.
医生袍、听筒  这套戏服很逼真
Smock, stethoscope. It's a great costume, Harry.
医生，你好吗？ 高，她真是廖医生
- So how are you, Doc? - No, Cole, this really is Dr. Lewicki.
我本来下班了
I was just about to go off duty.
但你想来看看我
You thought you'd come by to look me over.
来检查一下，你恢复视力了？
Well, it's not a bad idea. I figure your vision's restored?
看来是的
I think so.
有没有看到模糊、重迭的影像
Nothing's blurred? You're not seeing double?
有没有看到光晕和闪光？
No haloes around objects? Flashing lights?
慢着，你想做什么？ 看你的眼睛
- What are you going to do with this? - Look into your eyes.
医生
Doc, Doc.
你不是要找这东西吗？
Isn't this what you're really looking for?
很有趣
Well, that's interesting enough, Mr. Trickle,
但这不是我的专科
but it's just not my specialty.
她真的是医生？
She's the real thing?
我怎会在这时候作弄你
Well, I wouldn't play no joke on you in a situation like this.
对不起，我本来也不想笑的
Sorry, Cole, I'm trying not to smile.
给我滚
All right, get out.
走吧…
Get out. Get out of here.
再见
Get some rest, man.
我不对劲
I am not well.
我走得动
I can walk, God damn it.
医院不准你走路
Not as long as you're in this hospital you can't.
我不想见到他，请推快一点
I don't want to be next to this clown. You mind picking up the pace a little?
要药的话，你要找护士
Hey, man, if you want drugs, you have to see the nurse. Okay?
等待
Wait!
我的天
Get out of the way.
早安，两位先生  跟我来
Good morning, gentlemen. Right this way.
班先生和狄先生
So, neither Mr. Burns, nor in this case, Mr. Trickle
颅骨以内都没有受损
present any significant intracranial injury.
慢着，请简单地告诉我
Now hold it, Doc. Let's have that one in English.
他们有没有撞坏脑？
Did they mess up their squash or not?
脑部没有受损  至少跟意外发生前一样
Their brains are intact. As much as they were before the accident anyway.
你准许他们继续赛车？
You're willing to give them clearance to get back on a racetrack?
赛车是危险玩意
Well, that's obviously a dangerous way to spend your time.
我不想听哲学理论  我要医学意见
That's a philosophical objection, Doc, and I'm looking for a medical one.
我暂时不会准许他们赛车
I'm not inclined to give them clearance at this time.
废话  稍安勿躁
- That's total horseshit. - Gentlemen, please.
他们想听取别的医生的意见
I think they're saying they would like another opinion.
我们想见你的上司
We would like to talk to your boss.
你可以这样做  但我和韦医生
You're welcome to, of course, but Dr. Wilhaire and I have consulted
有一致的看法
and we're of the same opinion.
一至两周后再评估他们的情况
Which is a re-evaluation in a week or two.
谢谢，医生
Thank you, Doc.
我想跟他们说话
Now, we have a little something we have to say to the boys here
你不必留下来
and I don't think you necessarily need to hear it.
现在由大哥尊说话
Okay, Big John's turn.
如果你们想撞车死掉
If you wanna turn yourselves into a greasy spot
没问题
on a country road somewhere, go right ahead.
没有人会关心
I don't give a shit and I don't think anybody else does,
你们的死活
regardless of what they say to your face.
但不要在我的赛道生事
But you two monkeys are not going to do it on my racetrack.
你们听过日式检查吗？
Have you all heard of Japanese inspection?
日式检查
Japanese inspection.
日本人
You see, when the Japs get in a load of lettuce
不想外国生菜进口
that they're not sure they want to let in the country,
他们让生菜搁在码头
why, they just let it sit on the docks
日后才去检查
until they get good and ready to look at it.
后来所有生菜都腐坏了
By then of course, it's all gone rotten. Ain't nothing left to inspect.
生菜是容易腐坏的货品
In other words, lettuce is a perishable item
你们也一样
like you two monkeys.
如果你们再互相碰撞
You trade paint one more time, you so much as touch,
我会取消你们的资格
I'm gonna black-flag the two of you.
没收跑车
Gonna take apart your racecar for 300 laps.
等你们通过健康检查
Then if you pass the inspection,
重造跑车  我可能会让你们出赛
and you put your car back together, I might let you get back in the race.
你们要冰释前嫌
Now, just to show us there's no hard feelings,
今晚一起吃晚饭
we're all gonna go out to dinner together.
-我有别的约会  -我也一样
- I've got other plans. - Yeah, and so do I.
取消约会
Well, you're gonna have to change them.
你们要一起开车去餐厅
And not only that, you two are gonna drive to dinner together.
廖医生
Dr. Lewicki.
我想为高
I want to apologize for what happened with Cole
的行为道歉
when you come into the hospital room.
霍先生，不必介怀
Mr. Hogge, please, it's nothing to worry about.
你没有做错
And in any case it was hardly your doing.
我要负上责任
Well, that's just it, I believe it was.
不久前，狄高赢了达令顿大赛
You see, not too long ago after he won Darlington,
我们捉弄他
we played a trick on Cole.
我们找一位美女扮作公路女警
We dressed up a pretty girl in a highway-patrol uniform.
我们请她挑逗狄高
Anyway, we told her to get real ornery with him and she did.
你的意思是…  她真的挑逗狄高
- By ornery, you mean... - I mean, real ornery.
为什么告诉我这件事？
Why would you want me to know about this?
我不想你对高起了反感
I don't want you to hold a bad opinion of Cole.
他会害怕
I believe it scares him.
他需要你给他信心
He needs reassurance from you that he's okay.
毕竟你是他的医生
After all, you're his doctor.
我说完了
That's it.
医生
Doc.
有人说你误会我是公路女警
I heard you thought I was a highway-patrol officer.
谢谢你照顾我
I also want to thank you for taking care of me.
那是我的职责
It's my job.
你救了我
It's my life.
这次我们握手吧
Well, this time let's shake hands.
好  祝你好运  对不起
- Of course. Of course. - Good luck, Cole.
廖医生  我可以再见你吗？ 你一定会再见到我
- Dr. Lewicki, could I see you? - You will, I promise.
我的意思是…
No, I mean,
一起吃饭、看戏  我带你看赛车
have some dinner, go catch a movie. I'll take you to a race.
谢谢你邀请我
That's very sweet, really,
但我不会让你提早回跑道赛车
but it won't get you back on the track any faster.
不是…  我没有这想法
No, it's not what I meant.
你想怎样？ 我们要解决一个问题
- You got me here, now what? - Here's how I see this deal.
我不会让你开车去餐厅
Since you agree I ain't gonna let you drive this car to dinner
你也不会让我开车去餐厅
and I agree you ain't gonna let me drive this car to dinner,
只有一个解决方法
there's only one way to settle this.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
(汽车出租)
好主意
Absolutely.
添，听着
Let me tell you something, Tim.
如果你不能管束你的车手
If you can't control your race drivers any better than this,
你还是别做领队好了
you might consider sticking to something you can control.
回沙洛特-加龙省卖二手车吧
Like used cars in downtown Charlotte.
不算太迟
- Too close to call? - Yeah.
你迟到了  车有毛病
- You're late. - We had car trouble.
什么毛病？
What kind of car trouble?
是水箱有问题，对不对？
I believe it was the radiator. Wasn't it, Cole?
对，该是这样
Yes, Rowdy, I believe it was.
添，你认识医院的职员吗？
Tim, do you know anybody at Daytona Memorial?
认识院长，为什么？ 他是不是赛车迷？
- The chief of staff. Why? - Is he a race fan?
对不起
He was born in the South.
添想你和韦鲁斯见见面
Tim wanted you to meet Russ Wheeler.
他会暂时代替你为车队出赛
He's gonna be driving for us till you get your medical clearance.
我感到很荣幸，狄先生
It's a real pleasure to race your car, Mr. Trickle.
谢谢你来帮忙
Yeah, thanks for helping out.
添…  我想知道一位医生的住址
Yeah, Tim, I need a home address of a doctor...
我的驾驶技术
I'm only sorry I won't be able to drive it
比不上你
nearly as good as you though.
哈利，待会见
I'll see you later, Harry.
医院那位医生…
Yeah, the doctor that...
那位…
That...
什么？
What?
我很想吸引你注意
I was desperate to get your attention.
你成功了，我的家变成森林
Well, you got it. I walked into a jungle.
很美丽…但我不能来  我是医生，我得随时应诊
No, it's nicely extravagant, but really, I can't. I'm a doctor on call.
我是病人  我和洛甸要检受检查
And I'm a patient. Somebody has to re-examine me. I need clearance.
来检查我们，我带你看赛车
Come up here and do that. I'll take you to a race.
我不想浪费假期
Come on, I don't want to watch you guys going round and round in circles,
看你们打圈追逐
chasing each other like a pack of dogs on my day off.
那你放假来追逐我吧
Then how about chasing me on your day off?
我没有假期，我要24小时应诊
I don't have a day off. I'm on call 24 hours.
医生，假设你有两天假期…
Okay, Doctor, let's suppose you had a couple of days off...
糖…
Sugar. Sugar.
又没有什么节目
...with nothing else to do.
你想不想来北卡罗来纳？
Could I interest you in the North Carolina countryside?
这是假设？ 只是假设
- Speaking theoretically? - Speaking theoretically.
可能吧，你得说服我上司
Maybe. But you'd have to convince my boss.
好…你有多高？
Good. Good. How tall are you?
他说什么？
What did he say?
医生，到沙洛特-加龙省  检查那两个小子
"Doctor, fly to Charlotte and check those boys out."
我的天  你迫不及待
Boy, you're very quick.
你应该看看我赛车
You ought to see me drive.
洛甸不在这里
Rowdy's not here.
我叫他五时来找我们
Well, I told him to meet us at the infield by 5:00.
我先替高检查吧
Well, we should probably get started on Cole.
闭上眼睛  手掌向上
Close your eyes. Palms up.
张开眼睛  垂下双手
Open your eyes. Arms down.
看着我的手指
Follow my finger.
站立，双脚靠拢，闭上眼睛
Stand with your feet together and close your eyes.
踏前一步  张开眼睛
Walk one foot in front of the other. Open your eyes.
回桌子
And back on the table.
真难受
This is tough.
-检查总是难受的  -为什么？
- Examinations always are. - Why's that?
因为我可能会发现坏现象
Because I'm looking you over and I might not like what I see.
你会担心  凝视墙壁
That has to worry you. Pick a spot on the wall and look at it.
-别动  -我没有动
- Please, don't move. Your eyes. - I didn't move.
眼睛固定注视一个地方
Just focus on one spot.
你在看什么？ 视网膜
- What do you see? - The retina.
它怎样？
What does it look like?
很美丽
Very pretty, actually.
看够了吗？ 差不多了
- Seen enough? - Just about.
为什么那样做？ 测试你的反应
- What did you do that for? - It's the Babinski sign.
脚趾向上翘便有问题
If the toe goes up, you're in trouble.
你没事  穿上衣服，你可以参赛了
You're fine. Put on your clothes. You're cleared to race.
对不起，我无法控制自己
I'm sorry, it just drove me nuts in there.
你怎可以这么冷漠  我不是冷漠
- How could you ignore me like that? - I wasn't ignoring you!
我不是冷漠，我给你彻底检查
I wasn't ignoring you. I gave you a very thorough physical.
你不是有什么怪念头吧
You're not gonna do anything weird on my leg, are you, Cole?
不是
No.
我和哈利常常这样做
It's just something Harry and I work on together.
这叫做透气方法
It's called drafting.
两部车贴着行驶  会比一部车跑得快
One car tucks in behind another. Two cars can go faster than one.
它们能分担空气阻力
They divide the air resistance between them.
最有趣的地方是…
Now, here's where it gets interesting.
前面的车要踩尽油门  才能保持速度
The lead car has to floor it to hit 200 miles an hour.
后面的车不必耗用太多燃料
But the car that's stuck behind doesn't.
它一样会跑得很快  还能保持后劲
He can go just as fast and still have power in reserve.
到了最后一个弯口
So, when these two cars come off that last turn,
后面的车跑出来
the car that's in back can move out of the draft,
超越它的拍？，后来居上
and slingshot past the lead car, beat it to the finish line.
直闯凯旋大道
And he goes straight to Victory Lane.
你和哈利研究这战术？ 是
- You and Harry work on that, huh? - More or less.
是吗  除了赛车，你还想做什么？
Yeah, right. Is there anything you want to do besides racing?
我听从你的吩咐
Anything you say.
你一定还有其他
Cole, there must be something else
人生目标  迟早总会有
that you want to do in life, eventually.
让我告诉你我最不想做的事  我讨厌作弊
I can tell you what I don't want to be in life, that's a fraud.
我想证明我不是凭运气赛车
I want to know it's not just dumb luck that gets me around that racetrack.
但你不是想问这个
But that's not the question you're really asking.
我想问什么？
What's the question I'm really asking?
我怎么会跟这男人上床？ -我知道答案
- "How can I be in bed with this guy?" - I know the answer to that one.
-但你仍然怀疑
Maybe, but you're still asking it.
我这个脑科医生
"How could I, a brilliant brain doctor,
怎么会跟车手上床？
"be in bed with a guy who drives a car for a living?"
你有什么回应？ 转身
What's your response to that, by the way?
证明你的实力，令我尊敬你  来吧
Do something to make me respect you. Do it.
告诉我为何爱上赛车
Tell me what you love so much about racing.
追求速度
The speed.
控制速度
To be able to control it.
我能够控制不受控制的局面
To know that I can control something that's out of control.
要证明给你看？
I'd really have to show you.
证明给我看
Show me.
小时候我不想留在这里耕田
It's funny about this place. When I grew up, I hated farming.
我只想当赛车手  现在当了车手
All I wanted to do was work on racecars. Got into racing.
我只想存钱开农场
Now all I want to do is to make enough money to work on a farm.
嘉莉，我是珍妮，幸会
Hi, Claire, I'm Jennie. Nice to meet you.
幸会
Hi, nice to meet you.
-高，你好  -珍妮
- Hi, Cole. - Hey, Jennie.
我们打算在那山丘背后
Just beyond the top of that knoll,
盖一所房子
we're going to build our permanent home.
那要花多少钱？ -大约一千万元
- Costs much to build up there? - About $10 million.
-洛甸
Oh, Rowdy.
珍妮负责盖房子  她担任设计
Jennie's gonna do the building. She's designing the house.
我们想要没有人住过的新房子
We just want a place that nobody's ever lived in but us.
对吗？
Isn't that right, honey?
-你怎么了？ -晕船
- Rowdy, what is it? - I think I'm getting seasick.
但你从来都不会晕船
Seasick? You've never been seasick a day in your life.
你不想接受检查？
You didn't forget about the physical, did you?
我家族的人临死前才会看医生
Nobody in my family goes to a doctor unless they're dying.
病了不算是一回事
Just 'cause you ain't feeling good, shit.
站立，双脚靠拢
Stand with your feet together.
伸出双手
Put your arms out.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
小心  放松
Take it easy. Take it easy.
我扶着你
- I'm fine. I'm fine. - Yeah, I've got you.
我没事
- I'm fine. I'm fine. - All right.
你要回医院
We've got to get you back to Daytona.
我上司是全球最知名的  脑科医生
Bill Wilhaire, the head of neurosurgery, is my boss.
他是最棒的
He's as good as they come.
你在厕所呕吐？ 没有
- Did you get sick in there? - No.
-他呕吐  -洛甸
- He did, he got sick. - Rowdy.
没胆鬼，看到我晕你吓得想吐
You're one hell of a candy-ass. I faint and you throw up.
洛甸，你必须回医院
Rowdy, it's imperative that you get back to Daytona Memorial
见韦医生
and see Dr. Wilhaire.
一支新车队参加温斯顿杯赛
The report on the birth of another new Winston Cup team.
我背后有一部橙蓝色
Behind me, the bright orange and blue colors of Hardee's
的雪佛莱  谁是车主？当然是韦鲁斯
adorn this Chevrolet. Who's the driver? Well, to no one's surprise,
他曾替代狄高出赛
it's Russ Wheeler, the young man who subbed so superbly
技术过人
just weeks ago for the injured Cole Trickle.
胡说八道
Listen to this horseshit.
在我身旁的是车主杜添
Now joined by car owner, Tim Daland. Now, Tim, my question now is,
你旗下有两名好手
you've got two competitive spirits here,
会否构成冲突？
and will these competitive spirits cause you a conflict?
两支车队会保持独立
Well, of course, Jerry, we believe that we can
各自为政
maintain the integrity and the independence of these two race teams,
否则我们不会组织两支车队
otherwise, we wouldn't be doing it.
添，你会捧哪位车手？
Who will you be rooting for come Sunday, Tim?
每次越过狄高我会向他挥手
Well, I tell you, Jerry, I'll even wave to him every time I lap him.
(乔治亚州，亚特兰大)
你应该安装支架
These new tires are terrible. You should have put on scuffs.
你开得很好
You're doing good, Cole.
有点不稳定
I'm too loose.
这部车有问题
The car just feels all wrong.
什么事？ 高心情不好
- What's wrong? - Cole's upset.
为什么？ 他不想赛车
- What about? - About being in that racecar.
韦鲁斯越过八号车  他从内线爬你头
Wheeler just passed the eighth car. He's coming up on your inside.
我的天
Jesus!
发生什么事？ -引擎烧着了
- What happened? - The engine blew.
-为什么？ 我不是修车的
- How? - I'm not a mechanic, Harry.
嘉莉，我在乔治亚  洛甸在北卡罗来纳
Claire, I'm in Georgia today. Rowdy's in North Carolina.
得找人劝他来医院
Well, somebody better talk him into coming down here.
嘉莉  急症室有病人等你
Claire, we've got a trauma in the ER.
他脑出血  延迟就医
He's almost certainly hemorrhaging. The longer he ignores it,
只会令病情恶化
the more damage is gonna be done to his brain.
他是你的朋友
He's your friend, Cole.
-高在哪里？ -他讲电话
- Where's Cole? - He's on the phone.
给他一点私人时间
He could use a little privacy.
-他怎么了？
What's wrong with him?
-是你害了他
I'll tell you what's wrong in this deal, it's you, Tim.
你自食其果
You're a victim of your own goddamn creation.
两支车队…一山不能藏二虎
Two race teams! That's one too many roosters in the hen house.
韦鲁斯倒没有埋怨
It doesn't seem to bother Russ Wheeler.
那场车祸发生后
Oh, no, no, no. Ever since that Daytona crash,
狄高被视为滋事者
Cole's been called a troublemaker.
于是韦鲁斯肆意碰撞狄高
Wheeler figures he can bump and bam Cole all he wants.
我没有看到他撞狄高
I don't see Russ doing anything like that,
赛车会也没有发现他撞狄高
NASCAR doesn't see Russ doing anything like that.
你和赛车会的专家
I guess it ain't happening then,
都看不出来吧
under the watchful eyes of experts like you and NASCAR.
实情是这样
I tell you what is happening.
高跑得不好，他状态太差
Cole's not running good, he's not looking good,
赞助商不满意他的表现
and now he's got sponsor trouble.
-他们没有怪责你  -没有
- But you don't, is that it? - As far as that goes, no, I don't.
但我想留着赞助商和狄高
But I want to keep the sponsor and Cole.
他为我们打江山
He's the one that really made this happen for us
我没有忘本
and I haven't forgotten that, Harry.
是吗
Right. Right.
跟医生通电话？ 你们吵嘴？
You on the phone with the doc? Fighting?
不，她没时间谈话
She's too busy to talk right now.
杜添
Here's your owner, Tim Daland.
你怎样看这位年轻车手
What do you think about this young man, Tim?
鲁斯表现得很出色，我很满意
I think Russ ran a great race today. I'm really, really very pleased.
完成了102圈
One hundred and two laps complete,
车手暂时不准爬头
but we're under caution here at North Wilkesboro.
为什么高不探望洛甸？
How come Cole hasn't seen Rowdy yet?
高和所有车手一样
Cole's no different from any other driver.
什么意思？
What do you mean he's no different?
高当然不想见洛甸
Well, I mean, of course Cole doesn't want to see Rowdy.
车手不想忆起跑道上的意外
Drivers can't stand to be reminded of what can happen to them in a racecar.
他们不去医院，也不去葬礼
They don't go to hospitals, they don't go to funerals.
说服车手参加别人的葬礼…
You get a driver to a funeral before he's actually dead,
是一件比登天还难的事  进来
you made history, Doc.
他挡着我  好极了
- He's blocking me. - That's right.
添  走吧
Move the son of a bitch!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
狄高右边两个车胎都爆了
Trickle moving to the bottom of the track with both right-side tires flat.
韦鲁斯第一位冲线
Russ Wheeler takes the checkered flag...
韦鲁斯胜之不武
Russ Wheeler don't deserve to win, Tim.
赛车会和你都应该出来谴责他
If NASCAR won't call it lowdown, shit-assed racing, you better.
-赛车就是这样  -是吗
- It's just racing, Harry. - Oh, yeah?
-狄高太小器了  -是吗
- Cole overreacted. Yeah. - Oh, yeah?
换车胎
Change my tires.
为什么？赛事完了
I don't know what for, Cole. It's over.
换车胎
Change my tires.
维修站外面有事发生
There seems to be a little post-race activity just outside the pit lane.
可恶
You shit!
他毁了我两部车  两部车都被他毁了
He's destroyed both my cars. He's destroyed both my cars!
我炒他鱿鱼，炒你鱿鱼
He's fired! You're fired!
你们全都被炒鱿鱼，听到吗？ 你们全都要被炒鱿鱼
You're all fired. You hear me?
(希尔顿)
你拿行李，然后回医院？
Are you going to get your bags, head off to Daytona?
你去哪里？
Where are you going from here?
送你到机场，交还这部车
I'll take you to the airport, drop off the rental car,
然后坐飞机回沙洛特-加龙省
catch a flight to Charlotte.
要我陪你回去吗？
You want me to come with you?
你不用回医院？
You don't have to go back to the hospital?
我们可以去探望洛甸  是
- We could also try to see Rowdy. - Yeah.
有什么问题吗？ 没问题
- Is there anything wrong with that? - Of course not.
我只是忘记了  我知道
- I guess I just forgot about that. - Yeah, I know.
高
Cole!
我要下车
Let me out of the car, Cole.
我要下车…
Let me out of the car, Cole. Let me out of the car.
我要下车  你不停车我也要下车
Let me out of the car! Let me out or I'm getting out.
嘿…
Hey! Hey, hey!
嘉莉  别走
Claire! Wait. Just wait.
别跟着来，我会报警
- Get away or I'll call the police. - You'll what?
-什么？ -你听到的  报警吧
- You heard me. - Okay, call the police.
我会跟着你等你说话
But I'm not leaving until you talk.
-我无话可说  -我有话要说
- I've got nothing to say. - Well, I do!
好，说吧
Okay, great. Let's hear it.
就是这样？好
- That's it? Fine. - Just...
-来吧  -你不应该开车  不要再去马路、跑道
You shouldn't be driving a car anyway. Not on a road, not on a racetrack,
以及停车场
and not in a parking lot.
你自私、疯狂，你害怕
You're selfish, you're crazy and you're scared.
我没有害怕  你怕得要死
- I'm not scared. - You are scared to death.
你和洛甸一样
You and Rowdy, you have the same sickness. It's called denial.
不肯面对现实迟早会没命
And it's probably going to kill you both.
你说你想控制
You want to control something that's out of control,
无法控制的局面
that's what you said to me, wasn't it?
让我告诉你
I'm going to let you in on a little secret
所有人都知道…
that almost everybody else in this world automatically knows.
我们不能控制
Control is an illusion, you infantile egomaniac.
也无法预知未来
Nobody knows what's gonna happen next.
车、飞机、我们的身体  随时会出事
Not on a freeway, not in an airplane, not inside our own bodies,
四十个自大狂一起飚车  自然更危险
and certainly not on a racetrack with 40 other infantile egomaniacs.
没有人能控制任何事
Nobody knows and nobody controls anything.
你意识到这道理，于是你害怕
Now, you've gotten a glimpse of that and you're scared.
你失去勇气
You might not have the courage to race anymore.
你再不能赛车
You may never have had it.
你真讨厌
God, I hate you for this, you son of a bitch.
你逼我板起面孔说教
You make me sound like a doctor.
珍妮
Jennie.
你为什么来了？
Why are you here?
他在哪里？
Where is he?
-听说你失业了  -对
- I hear you're out of a job. - Yeah.
你脸色很差
You're not looking too good.
一天吃多少颗止痛药？
How many of these things do you chew every day?
你来做什么？
What did you come here for?
抓你去医院
To take you to the hospital.
若不是那个女医生
If it had been anybody but a damn woman doctor,
我早已回去赛车
I'd have been back on the track weeks ago.
是吗？ 是
- Is that right? - Yeah, that's right.
听着  断腿、心脏受伤
Listen, man, I've raced with my legs broke, heart bruised,
眼球快掉出来
eyes popping out of my head like they're on springs.
我还不是照样参赛
This is going to go away just like anything else.
这次也不会例外  我不会死
As far as I'm concerned, I'm going to live forever,
去了医院才会死
unless I go to some damn hospital where they
他们逼你脱鞋、闭上眼睛  然后你就死了
take your shoes off, and make you shut your eyes, and bang, you're dead.
这是什么奖杯？
What did you win this for?
这个…是那场赛事的？
This one right here. What did you win this for?
上面没写着吗？
Doesn't it say?
温斯顿杯
Yeah, it's the Winston Cup, buddy.
容易被人遗忘
Well, hell, that's an easy one to forget.
你的名字呢？你也忘了？
What's your name? Or has that slipped your mind, too?
去你的
- Screw you, man. - Okay.
去医院治好你的脑袋  或者留在这里敲脑袋
We can go down there and fix your head or we can fix it right here!
你选哪一样？
Now, what's it gonna be?
洛甸想见你
Rowdy would like to see you.
-他怎样？ -他还好
- How is he? - He's okay.
-你好吗？ -很好
- How are you? - Good.
他能否参加地通拿赛？
Think he'll make Daytona? It's not for a few months.
他会康复
I think he'll make it out of the hospital.
但他再不能赛车
But he'll never drive a racecar again.
这是韦医生，他替洛甸施手术
Cole, this is Dr. Wilhaire. He's going to be doing the surgery.
-我是狄高  -狄高
- Cole Trickle. - Cole.
他怎样？
So, how is he?
医生说我的脑部要动小手术
Well, the doc here says I need minor brain surgery.
也不算是小手术
Well, that's not exactly how I put it.
他脑袋太小，只能动小手术
Well, listen, Doc, any surgery on his brain is bound to be minor.
我想跟他单独谈谈
You all mind if I talk to this guy a second?
好
Of course.
脑部有一条血管爆裂了
They say I got a busted blood vessel in my brain.
他们想在我的头开洞取瘀血
So, they want to drill a hole in my head and get rid of the leaky blood.
我应该接受手术吗？
You think I should let them do it, Cole?
应该
Yeah.
换了是你，你会动手术？ 我会
- You'd let them if it was you? - I would.
好，我想请你帮我做一件事
Okay, then I've got to ask you to do something for me.
说吧
Well, name it.
驾驶我的车  你说什么？
- Drive my car. - What are you talking about?
地通拿大赛
Daytona.
你有足够时间准备出赛
No, Rowdy, you have plenty of time to get ready for Daytona.
不必找我
You don't need me.
我失去了赞助商  他们没有赞助我的跑车
I lost my sponsor. They put their money on me, not the car.
我不知道手术会否成功
Now, they ain't too sure I'm going to come out of this deal.
你说呢？
Are you?
我买了地，还没付钱
I've got a lot of land and a lot of plans I ain't paid for.
我的车要胜出
So the only way to get my sponsor back is to make sure
才会有赞助商找我
my car runs good at Daytona.
电视台会注意我的车
All that network TV shit, you know.
不必找我
Well, you don't need me.
这里还有其他车手
There's plenty of other drivers. You don't need me.
别来这一套，混蛋
Don't give me that mealy-mouthed shit, you son of a bitch.
我要找一个能登上五甲的车手
I got to put a driver in my car that'll finish in the top five,
否则赞助商不会为我付账
before my sponsors will pick up the tab for the year.
地通拿大赛后我可能会复出
Maybe after Daytona, maybe I can drive.
也可能无法复出
Maybe it'll be a different driver.
现在我要想办法养家
But in the meantime, I want the best for my family.
别推搪我
So don't you bullshit me, Cole.
你有什么理由不替我出赛？
Is there some other reason why I ain't good enough for you to drive for?
你答应我了？
Then you'll do it?
还以为你不肯帮我
Shit, man. You had me going.
现在谈细节吧  你和杜添签了什么合约？
Now, let's get down to business here. What's your deal with Daland?
我们改天再谈吧  失陪一会
Hell, we'll work that out, okay? Excuse me for a second.
高，什么事？ 告诉洛甸我会给他电话
- Cole, what's wrong? - Just tell Rowdy I'll call him.
不行…
No, no, no, no, sir!
不能合作，不想合作  代价太大
Can't use them. Don't want them. Couldn't afford them if I did.
你说什么？
What the hell are you talking about?
我说赛车手  我知道你和班洛甸的事
Racecar drivers. I know all about you and Rowdy Burns.
我不会为你们修车参赛
And I ain't setting up that car for Daytona or anywhere else, Cole,
但你可以进来
but you're welcome to come on in.
我们喝酒、瞎扯
We'll bring out the moonshine and start telling lies
同时找美人
and calling up the women.
赛车免谈，进来  好，不谈赛车
- But no talk about racing. Come on. - All right, no talk about racing.
贝克，来
Come on, Buck,
我跟你们赛跑
I'll race your ass.
我要走了，晚安
I believe I'm gonna take off. Good night, Harry.
为什么不帮我？
Why won't you set up the car?
自从那次意外中洛甸受伤后
Ever since you and Rowdy crashed at Daytona and Rowdy got sick,
你担心自己
you've been waiting for the other shoe to drop,
也会遇上不幸
waiting on something bad to happen to you.
他们说白毕地经常听到怪声
Just like Buddy Bretherton. He started hearing voices.
在哪个赛车场都听到
All kinds of them, everywhere. Atlanta, Richmond, Wilkesboro.
他听到一个讯息
And all of them only had but one thing to say,
离开跑车，下车…
"Get out of that racecar. Get out..."
在亚特兰大
You pegged the engine in Atlanta,
你把引擎烧坏
redlined the son of a bitch and blew it sky-high.
你是故意的
Done it deliberate. Done it deliberate.
转数标指着9400转
9,400 rpms according to the little telltale button.
你不想赛车，你不想死
You was worried if you didn't get out of that car right quick, you'd die.
我有没有说错了
Now call me a liar.
你没说错
You're not lying.
现在你还要谈什么？
All right. What the hell are we talking about then?
我想开洛甸的车参赛  你要帮我
Racing Rowdy's car at Daytona. I can't do it without you.
你是干不来的
You can't do it period.
我不会重返赛车场
And I ain't going back there, Cole.
白毕地不是死于心脏病  对吗？ 什么？
Buddy didn't really die of a heart attack, did he?
白毕地不是死于心脏病吧
真相你还是不知道的好
No, he didn't, but you don't wanna hear about it.
赛车会相信  是跑车的装置害死了他
NASCAR privately claimed the setup on the car is what killed Buddy.
你用薄气喉来减轻车身重量
You used thin-walled tubing to keep the weight down.
气喉爆裂
The exhaust fumes broke through the fire wall
毕地吸入一氧化碳
and carbon monoxide knocked Buddy out.
废话  撞墙的时候
Horseshit! When Buddy hit the wall at the third turn,
他还是嚷个不停
he was jabbering on the radio about as fast as he was driving.
什么一氧化碳
Carbon monoxide, my ass.
昏迷的人
That was the loudest-talking unconscious man
怎会说话
you ever heard in your life.
毕地胡思乱想，结果送命
Nothing killed Buddy but his imagination.
为什么不让他们调查死因  为什么？
Why didn't you let them investigate, Harry? Why? Why?
因为我早应该
'Cause I should have known better
阻止他参赛
than to let him drive in the first place.
白毕地
You see, Buddy...
最惹人讨厌
Buddy was a terrible pain in the ass. He really was.
他自认对车有认识
He thought he knew about cars,
所以他比你更无知
which made him twice as ignorant as you.
但是…
But still...
我看着他赛车
I look at guys like Buddy...
他可以把跑车发挥得淋漓尽致
I've seen him do things in my racecar that's absolutely unbelievable.
证明我没有枉费心机
That really showed me what I had done.
你会不自觉地
And then you see,
爱上他这类人
you're gonna automatically have to sort of love that guy.
不论你喜不喜欢他
Whether you want to or not.
白毕地
Buddy Bretherton.
哈利，我想问你一件事
I have to ask you something, Harry.
在撞墙之前
Now, before Buddy hit the wall,
毕地在赛道上表现如何？
how was he actually doing in that race?
该死的
- You ornery, no good... - Hey, hey...
我那部车就看你的了
You set up that car. You set up the car.
不要再赛车，你会死  你会死，听到吗？ 你会死
If you get back in that car, you'll die. You'll die. You hear?
我不开我的车，我开洛甸的车
I'm not getting back in my car, I'm getting in Rowdy's.
你真是蠢得可怜
Well, I see how you're dumb enough to be a race driver.
开他的车就可以避过厄运？
You think you'll hide from your bad luck in his car?
何必为洛甸冒险？
What the hell for? For Rowdy?
为着拿奖杯，他会开车撞你
If he could run tomorrow, he'd crash you to win the race!
他不是好人
He's mean.
为什么帮他？ 因为他请我帮忙
- He's no particular friend, so why? - Because he asked me to.
废话，你舍不得放弃赛车
Horseshit! You just wanna race again.
-是，你也一样  -是
Yeah. And so do you.
但你心里害怕
Well, you're scared.
是，你也一样
- You're scared. - Yeah, and so are you.
是
Yeah.
怎么了？
What?
我需要参赛
I need this, Harry.
除了赛车我一无所有
I don't have anything else.
是你给我生命
You've given me a life.
我不想失去生命
God damn it, I don't want to lose it.
让我出赛
Just put me in that racecar.
让我证明你没有枉费心机
Let me be the one to show you what you've done.
相信我
Just trust me.
让我开车，我不会令你失望
Let me drive, Harry. I won't make a fool out of you.
我…  我不能预知后果
I honestly just wouldn't know how this deal's going to turn out, Cole.
你懂的
You know.
我也不能
Neither do I, Harry.
清凉的气温适合你
I'm setting up for cool weather.
要是烈日当头
But if that sun breaks after you're on the track,
你会跑得不稳定
you're liable to run real loose real quick.
我不想你担心，但高应付不来
I don't wanna worry you enough, but Cole's not ready for that.
他改变了
He's changed. See, he's changed.
如果你失去控制  他会不知所措
You cannot get out of control and expect him to bring you right back.
他会伤害你，你会伤害他
He's liable to hurt you, you're liable to hurt him.
我也无能为力，所以…
I couldn't handle that. So...
你要照顾他，行吗？
You've got to take care of him. All right?
你要照顾他
You've got to take care of him.
这不是我想要的答案
This is not the kind of answer I'm looking for from you.
地通拿赛道
Daytona is a tough racetrack.
难度很高
And I'm sure, myself and everybody,
我们会留意狄高
we're going to keep an eye on Cole to see
看看他能否应付紧急场面
if he's there, you know, all his reflexes and everything.
他驾驶技术高明
He's plenty capable of running that racecar good
那次意外…
and I don't think he has any kind of
相信不会影响他的表现
effects from the accident that would be a factor in the way he performs.
他回来真好
I'm glad he's well enough to come back
希望能击败他
and I hope I beat him at the same time.
很多人不喜欢他
You know, a lot of guys don't like him.
他很有天分
And it's just the situation where the guy's got a lot of talent.
他只是一心想取胜
He's wide open, he doesn't think about anything else,
一心想取胜
he just wants to win. I like that.
车祸发生后，他对自己和其他车手都是个危险人物
Since the crash, he's been a danger to himself and to other drivers.
如果他接近我  我会把他逼向墙边
But if he comes near me, I'm going to put him in the wall.
就是这么简单
Simple as that.
但我相信  我只会在倒后镜见到他
I don't expect I'll see too much of him. Except in my rearview mirror.
进来
Come in.
哈利说你不会介意我来看你
Harry said you wouldn't mind if I stopped by.
洛甸怎样？ 他日渐康复
- How's Rowdy? - He's getting better every day.
因为你说
Especially since you told him how much
你很想为他出赛
you were looking forward to getting in his racecar.
我说谎
So I lied.
你在想什么？
What are you thinking?
我想知道你在想什么
Just how much I'd like to know what you're thinking.
每个人都一样
I guess everybody's the same.
想活得开心
You've got to be good at your job
就要把工作做好
before you can enjoy the rest of your life.
这是我的工作
This is my job.
我唯一的专长
It's all I know.
我不敢看你出赛
You know I can't watch you do this.
嘉莉
Claire.
我不怕受伤，我只怕一事无成
I'm more afraid of being nothing than I am of being hurt.
送我出去吧
Walk me out?
欢迎莅临参观  地通拿500大赛
We welcome you to the Daytona 500, the Super Bowl of motor racing events.
今天的大热门是韦鲁斯
Certainly among the favorites for today's race
他驾驶十八号跑车
has to be Russ Wheeler driving the number 18 Hardee's sponsored car.
车迷都相信他
He has certainly given race fans something to talk about
今天能夺标
after winning the pole for today's event.
狄高再战江湖
But don't count out Cole Trickle,
不容忽视
who is returning to Daytona for the first time
去年七月他在这赛道遇上意外
since his near-fatal accident here last July.
你说你们没有赞助商
Told me you guys didn't have a sponsor.
他们给的钱只够用来贴商标
Well, they gave us just about enough money to put their name on the car.
添  高
- Tim. - Cole.
有什么问题？
Why is the hood up? What's wrong with the car?
别担心，我们换引擎
Take it easy. We had to change engines.
忘了拉紧油管
We forgot to tighten the oil line.
为什么要换引擎？ 滤油器有金属碎片
- Why did you have to change engines? - Found some metal in the oil filter.
从哪里找来这引擎？ 偷来的
- Where did you get the engine? - Well, we stole it.
嘉莉，叫他上车
Claire, put the boy in his car,
他可能会作贼心虚不敢上车
tell him to get out on the track before he starts sweating, all right.
你会开车离开？
So, you're going to get in your car and take off?
小心驾驶
Drive carefully.
各位选手，请开动引擎
Gentlemen, start your engines.
地通拿500大赛开始了
We are underway. The Daytona 500 is on.
200圈赛事，进入56圈  韦鲁斯领先
We are 56 laps into this 200-lap event and Russ Wheeler is in the lead.
47.01秒，第一位跑45.90秒  你在最后位置
47:01. Lead is 45:90. You're running last.
高，你怎么了？
What's going on, Cole?
你没事吧
Are you all right?
刚跑完半程，韦依然领先
Just past the halfway mark and Wheeler still leads.
三号弯角有意外
There's a crash at turn three, and some oil at the bottom of the track.
跑道有油迹
The lead is just taken.
其他车在滑行，你小心点
Cars are sliding down from the top of the track, so watch yourself.
走外圈吧  找一条路冲过去
You'd better go high, Cole. Pick a line you can drive through.
高，你没事吧  请回答我
Cole, are you all right? Answer me, please.
绕过车堆，你做得到的
Go around those wrecks. You can drive through it.
我对你有信心
I know it. I know it in my heart.
我冲出来了
I'm through it, Harry!
我要撇下它们
I'm out of here.
狄高升至第九位，后劲凌厉
Cole's moved up to ninth. He's coming on strong.
十八号车依然领先
Russ Wheeler in car number 18 continues to lead the way,
但狄高急起直追
but the man on the move is Cole Trickle.
我要突围而出
I'm gonna make a hole to get through here.
好了
Here we go.
韦逼我撞根斯，根斯失控了
Wheeler knocked me into Ganz. Ganz spun out.
他走外圈
He's going high.
可恶
God damn it!
狄高爬头领先
And on the high side of the track, Trickle takes the lead.
高，加油
Go, Cole!
对，就是要这样
This is it, this is what it's all about.
只剩下23圈，狄高领先
With just 23 laps to go, Cole Trickle is leading.
-别放过他  -我会教训他
- Take him now, Russ. - He's all mine.
哈利，油门卡着了  我踩尽了油门
The accelerator is stuck, Harry. It's stuck, it's on the floorboard.
我没法减速
I can't slow down.
踩离合器，让引擎燃烧
Step on the clutch and let the son of a bitch blow it.
这回玩完了
It's over, Cole.
狗娘养的
Son of a...
高，你没事吧
Cole, you okay?
油门没事了
The good news is the accelerator is fixed,
但波箱有问题
the bad news is the transmission is screwed.
我回修理站
I'm coming in.
他们出局了？ 四十五秒后自会出局
- Are they out of the race, yet? - They will be in about 45 seconds.
我要走在领航车前面
That's the pace car.
否则完了
Get me out in front of the pace car or the race is over for us!
低波有问题  给他高波齿轮
- The linkage is all twisted. - Just give him the high gear.
让我走
Get me out there.
行了
I got it.
领航车来了
Pace car's on its way.
快点
Let's go.
快点…  快点…
- Come on, man, come on. - Go! Go! Go!
你们去帮他，去吧
Get out there and help them! Go! Go! Go!
成功了，做得好
All right, all right, we made it. Good work.
-谢谢你  -别客气
I owe you one.
你不能这样做，那不是你的车
Hey, you can't do that. That's not your car.
那引擎是我给他的
It's my engine in that car, I gave him that engine,
我的人可以推他的车
and that's what my boys are pushing.
等绿旗出现，然后全速前进
Cole, you better be at max speed when the green flag drops.
领航车离开
The pace car pulls off the track.
大会出示绿旗
The green flag is out and racing resumes.
韦仍然领先  好
Wheeler broke away, he's still in the lead.
我在什么位置？
- Where am I? - Running ninth.
八圈
- How many laps to go? - Eight.
我和韦相距多少？
What's the interval between me and Wheeler?
鲁斯，狄高由第五位追上来
Trickle's fifth and moving up fast, Russ.
记得我吗？
Remember me?
我会紧贴着鲁斯的车
I'm going to draft Wheeler, make him pull me around the track.
那混蛋紧跟着我
The son of a bitch is on my ass.
他想在外线爬头  我会逼他撞墙
He's going to take me on the outside. I'm going to put him in the wall.
发生什么事？ 他要令他上当
- What's going on, Cole? - I'm just setting him up, Harry.
大会出示白旗，还有一圈
There's the white flag. One lap to go.
最后一圈了
Last lap, Cole.
不要再这样下去  哈利，他输定了
- Don't keep this up, Cole, please. - Harry, this guy's going down.
最后一圈，小心  他想爬头
Last turn, be careful. He's going to try and slingshot past you, Russ.
少担心，高总是从外圈爬头
Don't worry, I know Cole. He always goes to the outside.
哈利，这一招送给你
This one's for you, Harry.
他走外圈
He's going high.
他走内圈
He's going low!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
狄高首先冲线
Here come the cars to the finish line, it's Cole Trickle taking the win.
好
All right! All right!
我以为你走了  我说谎
- I thought you weren't gonna watch. - I lied.
-哈利呢？ -不知道…
- Where's Harry? - I don't know.
哈利
Harry.
说句话吧
Harry, say something, will you?
我无话可说
I really can't. I can't.
你猜不到会这样吧
You didn't know how this one was going to turn out, did you?
正如你所说
It's like you said.
赛车难不倒你
There's nothing you can't do in a racecar.
我们赢了  -我们赢了  -是
- We won. We won. - I know. Yeah.
你走得动吗？要我背你吗？
Now, can you walk, or am I going to have to carry you?
去哪里？
Where to?
凯旋大道  好
- Victory Lane. - Yeah.
走路？
Walk? Hell,
看谁跑得快
I'll race your ass.